Banerjee, Soumesh

+91 8591 5322 74[\omega] soumeshbanerjee@live.com[\omega] soumeshbanerjee.github.io

Current Location is Shanghai Willing to Relocate Visa Sponsorship Required Notice Period of ~1 Month

Profile

Software Engineer with hands-on experience on every phase of product development, worked as individual contributor as well product architect. Focused on delivering quality product on time. I am very energetic, enthusiastic and a team player dedicated to efficiently solve the problems. Always keen to learn and implement new technologies that can help in achieving a goal in better and faster ways.

I have experience in working in Office Workspace, On-Site and Remotely and have sound experience in Cross Platform Tooling, Frontend, Backend, Mobile, Distributed Systems, IoT, Embedded and lot of other technologies.

I am also active on tech-communities like, *StackOverflow*, *Github*, *NPM*, etc., and also love to contribute to open-source projects

Experience

Software Engineer

May 2019 - Current

Espressif Systems (Shanghai, China)

• Responsible for designing, developing and documenting the open-source <u>VSCode Extension</u> for <u>ESP-IDF Framework</u> serving the end-user with ease to build, test, deploy and debug their code in <u>ESP32 SoC</u>

Senior Software Development Engineer

June 2018 - May 2019

Kony India Pvt. Ltd. (Hyderabad, India)

- Responsible for <u>designing and developing</u> a <u>tool</u> which aims at <u>eliminating the coding</u> <u>efforts in UI Testing</u> for the end-users.
- Responsible for <u>designing of a framework</u> for <u>cross-platform network traffic analyser</u>, this aims at <u>empowering developers</u> by helping them to <u>determine the bottleneck</u>, <u>errors</u>, and <u>capture metrics</u>; was also responsible for the <u>complete development of the same in iOS</u>.
- Responsible for complete designing and development of a <u>single code multi-channel</u> module for the <u>popular home assistant</u> in the market like Alexa, Cortana, Google Home, etc., this aims at <u>an existing customer</u> with a mobile app., to <u>easily extend</u> their services for the <u>voice assistant space</u>.
- Responsible for designing of a <u>USB based communication</u> framework for <u>cross-platform</u> which aims at communication between the host OS and iOS Devices, perform payload delivery, multiplex and stream data over tcp, install IPA, etc.

Software Development Engineer

Sept. 2017 - June 2018

Kony India Pvt. Ltd. (Hyderabad, India)

• Responsible for designing and development of a <u>decentralised</u>, <u>distributed</u>, <u>highly scalable</u>, and available task manager with hot plugin loading system, which is then consumed by <u>several internal teams</u> for distributed Automation, build or CI system.

Experience

• Responsible for complete designing of a <u>plugin-rich</u>, <u>rule-based code analysis tool</u>, that aims at <u>eliminating dead code</u>, <u>remove unused resources</u>, etc., which interim provides a <u>significant runtime</u> and the load-time boost for the applications.

Associate Software Engineer

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

Kony India Pvt. Ltd. (Hyderabad, India)

• Laid the foundation of the Automation Framework, which was then used across team to build test case upon, provided a complete mechanism to test-report-and-repeat CI Arch

Education

Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar, Punjab, India

Aug. 2013 - Jun. 2017

Graduation - B. Tech (Computer Science) - CGPA: 8.38

DAV Public School, Dhanbad, Jharkhand, India

Apr. 2010 - Mar. 2013

AISSCE (CBSE) - Percentage: 76%

AISSE (CBSE) - CGPA: 8.4

Expertise

iOS; Objective-C; Swift; Go-lang; Rust; Linux; AWS; VueJS; NodeJS; Bootstrap; Elastic Search; Redis; MongoDB; MySQL; JIRA; Markdown; Git; PlantUML; IOT; RPi; Arduino; SDR; Chrome Extensions; Neural Network;

Socials

/soumeshbanerjee

in/sudoo

/users/2256024